Guide to the Department of Athletics, Yale University, Records Documenting Baseball
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Department of Athletics, Yale University, records documenting baseball
1874-2001
RU 61
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
17.5
(16 boxes) and 3 microfilm reels
The records consist of reports, score books, publications, and scrapbooks maintained primarily by the Department of Athletics documenting baseball at Yale.
Yale University. Dept. of Athletics
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 38-B (YRG 38-B), Records documenting specific sports at Yale.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were gifts of various donors, 1979-1986; and transferred from the Department of Athletics, 2005.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Scrapbooks, Accession 2006-A-111, are available on microfilm. Patrons must use HM 180 instead of the originals.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of reports, score books, publications, and scrapbooks maintained primarily by the Department of Athletics documenting baseball at Yale.
Existence and Location of Copies
Scrapbooks, Accession 2006-A-111, are available on microfilm.
Baseball; College sports; Scrapbooks; Yale University Athletic Association; Yale University -- Baseball; Yale University -- Sports; Yale University. Dept. of Athletics
- Reports of the 1889 season by A. H. Hough, Accession 1979-A-052
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  - Reports, 1889 (Box 1)
- Score books kept by Mrs. David L. Daggett, 1928-1972; Accession 1986-A-087
  Scope and Contents
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Score books
    - 1928 May 1- 1930 May 13 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1930 May 17 - 1937 June 25 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1932 May 3 - 1935 June 21 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1938 April 11 - 1941 May 21 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1941 May 24 - 1947 May 3 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1947 May 7 - 1949 April 30 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1949 May 14 - 1952 May 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1952 May 16 - 1961 April 25 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1954 April 10 - 1956 April 14, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1958 May 6 - 1972 May 13 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1961 May 13 -1964 June 21 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous: score cards, schedules, clippings (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Records of the baseball team, 1874-2001; Accession 2006-A-101
  Restricted until January 1, 2036
  - Scorebooks
    - 1904-1912, 1914, 1924-1947 (Box 1)
    - 1948-1973 (Box 2)
    - 1973-2001 (Box 3)
  - General Administration Records (includes statistics, correspondence, Ethan Allen draft publications and baseball association materials), 1929-1989 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous Publications, 1929-1997 (Box 4)
  - Newsletters, 1981-1982 (Box 4)
  - Baseball team trip to Hawaii, 1935 (Box 5)
  - Yale baseball information, 1991, 1994 (Box 5)
  - Baseball series records and scores, 1874-1936 (Box 5)
- Scrapbooks maintained by the baseball team, 1912-1945; Accession 2006-A-111
  The scrapbooks are available on microfilm. Patrons must use film HM180.
  - Scrapbooks
    - Vol. 1, 1912-1915 (Box 1, Reel 1U)
    - Vol. 2, 1916 (Box 2, Reel 1U)
    - Vol. 3, 1916-1921 (Box 3, Reel 1U)
    - Vol. 4, 1921-1927 (Box 4, Reel 2U)
    - Vol. 5, 1923-1924 (Box 5, Reel 2U)
    - Vol. 6
      - ca. 1926 (Box 9, Reel 2U)
      - 1928-1930 (Box 5, Reel 2U)
    - Vol. 7, 1931-1935 (Box 6, Reel 2U)
    - Vol. 8, 1935-1941 (Box 7, Reel 3U)
    - Vol. 9, 1942-1945 (Box 8, Reel 3U)